United Auto Workers, Local 1010 Records 2002.0007
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
United Auto Workers, Local 1010 Records
1957-1988.
2002.0007
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
0.75 Linear feet
Documents and publications pertaining to the United Auto Workers (UAW) union, local 1010, and its representation of employees of Lycoming Engines in Stratford, Connecticut. The records contain published agreements, manuals, booklets, newsletters and assorted ephemera from the union, spanning the years 1957 to 1988.
.75 linear feet.
History
The United Auto Workers (UAW) is a labor union which has represented workers in the aerospace, automobile, and agricultural industries in the United States since 1935. The United Auto Workers were originally a part of the Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO), but grew rapidly during the 1930s, 1940s, and 1950 to become an important advocate for workers' rights in the United States. Officially known as the United Automobile, Aircraft and Agricultural Implement Workers of America the United Auto Workers Local 1010 was a Connecticut branch of the union, representing workers at Lycoming Engine.
Located in the town of Stratford, Connecticut, Lycoming manufactured turbine engines, producing between six and seven hundred engines a year by 1961. However, as the demand for engines diminished by the 1980s Lycoming began to shift their operations elsewhere, and in 1986 sold the company to Textron. By 1999 the Stratford based plant was sold again, this time to AlliedSignal, later becoming a part of Honeywell Aerospace.
The records focus primarily on the period when the plant was owned and operated by Lycoming Engine. The documentation is primarily related to the relationship between Lycoming and United Auto Workers Local 1010 during the 1950s, 1960s, 1970s, and 1980s.
Scope and Content
The records consist of publications and materials pertaining to the United Auto Workers union, local 1010, and its representation of employees of the Lycoming AVCO Manufacturing Corporation. The records consist of published agreements, manuals, booklets, newsletters and assorted ephemera from the union. Spanning the years 1957 to 1988, the records contain wage and benefit guides, weekly memorandums and newsletters, membership cards, retirement benefit guides, and "Hot News" fliers published by the United Auto Workers union.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of Connecticut labor records. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Unknown.
Automobile industry workers--Labor unions.; Contracts.; Labor union; Labor unions--Connecticut.; Publications.
- Series I: Records, undated, 1957-1985
  - Agreements, 1957-1972 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Agreements, 1982-1985 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Benefits, 1979 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Constitution and By-Laws, 1964 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Election materials, [1966] (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Grievance Procedure, 1967 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Group Insurance, 1973-1985 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Guide of Tentative Agreement, 1985 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Hot News, 1978-1986 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Membership materials, undated (Box 2:, Folder 10)
  - Newsletter, 1977-1986 (Box 2:, Folder 11)
  - Pension and Retirement booklets, undated, 1982 (Box 2:, Folder 12)
  - Skilled Trades, 1985 (Box 2:, Folder 13)
  - Steward's Memoranda, 1977-1981 (Box 2:, Folder 14)
  - Steward's Wage and Benefits Guidebook, 1985-1988 (Box 2:, Folder 15)
  - UAW—Adopted Resolutions and Buttons, undated, 1985 (Box 2:, Folder 16)